<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY % general-entities SYSTEM "../general.ent">
  %general-entities;
]>

<sect1 id="ch-intro-askforhelp">
  <?dbhtml filename="askforhelp.html"?>

  <title>도움말</title>

  <note>
    <para>
      In case you've hit an issue building one package with the LFS instruction,
we strongly discourage posting the issue directly onto the upstream support
channel before discussing via a LFS support channel listed in <xref
linkend="ch-intro-resources" role='.'/> Doing so is often quite inefficient
because the upstream maintainers are rarely familiar with LFS building
procedure.  Even if you've really hit an upstream issue, the LFS community
can still help to isolate the information wanted by the upstream maintainers
and make a proper report.
    </para>

    <para>
      If you must ask a question directly via an upstream support channel, you
shall at least note that many upstream projects have the support channels
separated from the bug tracker.  The <quote>bug</quote> reports for asking
questions are considered invalid and may annoy upstream developers for these
projects.
    </para>
  </note>

  <para>이 책의 내용을 따라가다가 문제나 궁금한 점이 생기면 우선 <ulink url="&faq-root;#generalfaq"/>에 있는
FAQ 페이지를 확인해 보십시오. 많은 질문에 대한 답변이 이미 그곳에 있습니다. 만약 해당 페이지에서 답을 찾을 수 없다면, 문제의
원인을 찾아보십시오. 다음 힌트 문서에서 문제 해결에 관한 지침을 얻을 수 있습니다: <ulink
url="&hints-root;errors.txt"/>.</para>

  <para>If you cannot find your problem listed in the FAQ, search the mailing lists
at <ulink url="&lfs-root;search.html"/>.</para>

  <para>We also have a wonderful LFS community that is willing to offer assistance
through the mailing lists and IRC (see the <xref
linkend="ch-intro-resources"/> section of this book). However, we get
several support questions every day, and many of them could have been easily
answered by going to the FAQ or by searching the mailing lists first.  So,
for us to offer the best assistance possible, you should first do some
research on your own. That allows us to focus on the more unusual support
needs. If your searches do not produce a solution, please include all the
relevant information (mentioned below) in your request for help.</para>

  <sect2>
    <title>Things to Mention</title>

    <para>Apart from a brief explanation of the problem being experienced, any request
for help should include these essential things:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The version of the book being used (in this case &version;)</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The host distribution and version being used to create LFS</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The output from the <xref linkend='version-check'/> script</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The package or section the problem was encountered in</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The exact error message, or a clear description of the problem</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Note whether you have deviated from the book at all </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <note>
      <para>Deviating from this book does <emphasis>not</emphasis> mean that we will not
help you. After all, LFS is about personal preference.  Being up-front about
any changes to the established procedure helps us evaluate and determine
possible causes of your problem.</para>
    </note>

  </sect2>

  <sect2>
    <title>Configure Script Problems</title>

    <para>If something goes wrong while running the <command>configure</command>
script, review the <filename>config.log</filename> file. This file may
contain errors encountered during <command>configure</command> which were
not printed to the screen. Include the <emphasis>relevant</emphasis> lines
if you need to ask for help.</para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2>
    <title>컴파일 문제</title>

    <para>컴파일 문제의 원인을 파악하는 데는 화면 출력 내용과 다양한 파일의 내용이 모두 유용하게
쓰입니다. <command>configure</command> 스크립트와 <command>make</command> 실행 시 화면 출력이
도움이 될 수 있습니다. 출력 전체를 포함할 필요는 없지만, 관련된 모든 정보는 반드시 포함해야 합니다. 여기
<command>make</command> 화면 출력에서 포함해야 할 정보의 유형을 보여주는 예시가 있습니다.</para>

<screen><computeroutput>gcc -D ALIASPATH=\"/mnt/lfs/usr/share/locale:.\"
-D LOCALEDIR=\"/mnt/lfs/usr/share/locale\"
-D LIBDIR=\"/mnt/lfs/usr/lib\"
-D INCLUDEDIR=\"/mnt/lfs/usr/include\" -D HAVE_CONFIG_H -I. -I.
-g -O2 -c getopt1.c
gcc -g -O2 -static -o make ar.o arscan.o commands.o dir.o
expand.o file.o function.o getopt.o implicit.o job.o main.o
misc.o read.o remake.o rule.o signame.o variable.o vpath.o
default.o remote-stub.o version.o opt1.o
-lutil job.o: In function `load_too_high':
/lfs/tmp/make-3.79.1/job.c:1565: undefined reference
to `getloadavg'
collect2: ld returned 1 exit status
make[2]: *** [make] Error 1
make[2]: Leaving directory `/lfs/tmp/make-3.79.1'
make[1]: *** [all-recursive] Error 1
make[1]: Leaving directory `/lfs/tmp/make-3.79.1'
make: *** [all-recursive-am] Error 2</computeroutput></screen>

    <para>이 경우, 많은 사람들이 마지막 부분만 포함합니다:</para>

<screen><computeroutput>make [2]: *** [make] Error 1</computeroutput></screen>

    <para>이것만으로는 문제를 진단할 정보가 충분하지 않습니다. 무언가 잘못되었다는 사실만 나타낼 뿐, <emphasis>무엇이</emphasis>
잘못 되었는지 안 보여주기 때문입니다. 위의 예시처럼 섹션 전체를 저장해야 하는데, 실행된 명령과 그와 관련된 모든 에러 메시지가 거기
들어있기 때문입니다.</para>

    <para>인터넷에서 도움을 요청하는 방법에 관한 훌륭한 글을 <ulink
url="http://catb.org/~esr/faqs/smart-questions.html"/>에서 온라인으로 볼 수 있습니다. 이
문서를 읽고 힌트를 따라 보십시오. 그러면 여러분이 필요한 도움을 받을 가능성이 높아질 겁니다.</para>

  </sect2>

</sect1>
